# **Enrique Marcos**

Cologne, Germany · enrmarc@gmail.com · enrmarc.com

For the past 7 years I have been working as a software engineer in Spain and Germany. Focused on building web products, but interested in computer science in general. I approach my duties with humility, and avoid clever tricks like the plague.

# Previous Experience

real.digital GERMANY Software Engineer Aug. 2017-

Stack: PHP (Zend & Symfony), Vue.js, Go, Kafka, Docker, K8s.

# Universität Duisburg-Essen

GERMANY

Researcher Oct. 2016-Jun. 2017

Thesis topic: Text Mining applied to Learning Analytics. Collide research group.

#### **Cognizant Technology Solutions**

Spain and Belgium

Aug. 2014–Jun. 2016

Software Engineer at KBC Bank NV

Worked for a Belgium bank on its web banking application (KBC Touch):

- · Rebuilt the "sign-up for a Checking & Savings Account for new customers" flow, making KBC Touch the most user-friendly banking app in Belgium in 2016.
- · Built high-level reusable components as part of the internal frontend team using AngularJS, Coffeescript, Jade (now Pug), and Sass.

Stack: AngularJS, Java, Git, Scrum, Atlassian tools, and Node.js based automation tools.

Spain Cresertec S.L. Dec. 2012-May. 2014

Software Engineer

- · Built from scratch an e-commerce site with PayPal as the payment gateway.
- · Built a business-oriented website builder that provided: mobile-optimized design templates, boilerplate sections with pre-filled text and images, persistent backend storage (MongoDB).
- · Developed internal native Android apps (with their respective HTTP APIs).

Stack: PHP (CakePHP), Python (Flask), JavaScript, Java (Android), MySQL, MongoDB, Git.

## Education

M.Sc. in Computer Science. Universität Duisburg-Essen. Germany. Master thesis.	Jun. 2017
M.Sc. in Computer Science. University of Valladolid. Spain. Graduated with honors.	Jun. 2016
B.Sc. in Computer Science. University of Valladolid. Spain.	Fun. 2012

## Skills

Solid knowledge of computer science fundamentals. Comfortable working on unix-like environments. Started my career with the LAMP and MEAN stacks. Nowadays working with PHP, JS, Go and containerized services. English (fluent), Spanish (native), German (basic).